+1 (650) 561-5385 Bay Area, California honghao.zhang@uwaterloo.ca

HongHao Zhang

honghaoz.com github.com/honghaoz linkedin.com/in/honghaozhang

SUMMARY

Experienced and extremely passionate in iOS development, has been coding in Swift since it's released and used it for recent projects including server-side projects.

Constantly striving to learn new technologies and hacking in daily life.

SKILLS & EXPERTISE

Programming Language:

- Proficient: Swift, Objective-C
- Experienced: JavaScript, C/C++, Python, HTML, CSS
- Familiar: React, Ruby, Java, SQL, Scheme, Bash

Software Engineering: RESTful API, Git, Jira, TDD/BDD, Node.js, MongoDB, DigitalOcean, AWS, Heroku

WORK EXPERIENCES

Facebook Inc., SF Bay Area - Software Engineer

Oct 2017 - Present

- Joined Instagram Video Infra team.
- · Working on video transcoding and uploading infra framework for Instagram iOS app.

theScore Inc., Toronto - iOS Engineer

Jun 2015 – Jul 2017

- Responsible for the maintenance of esports and the Socre iOS app. New design for esports 2.0 and the Score 6.0
- · Shared Toolkit: Searching, View controller transition Animator, SwipeTableViewCell, Drop-Down menu, Chart

DogSync, Montréal - iOS Developer (Contract)

Dec 2014 - May 2015

- Acted as lead developer for front-end implementation, collaborated directly with the designer
- Responsible for implementation of all views and view controllers, used Adaptive Layout (constraint-based)

Wattpad Inc., Toronto - iOS Developer (Intern)

Aug - Dec 2014

- · Responsible for design update for iOS8 and native resolution support for iPhone 6 and iPhone 6 Plus
- · Created constraint-based views, such as accessory keyboard for editor, used Auto Layout and Core Graphics

PROJECTS

Open Source Libraries (iOS, Swift, GitHub)

Jan 2014 - Present

- <u>Ji (戟)</u> an XML/HTML parser for Swift
- AutoKeyboardScrollView Handy UIScrollView subclass to handle keyboard avoidance
- Swift Google Maps API Swift wrapper on Google Maps Web Services APIs, provide native data models
- <u>ChouTi (抽屉)</u> Personal iOS toolkit, includes reusable UI components, common data structures and extensions

2048X - 2048 with AI solver (iOS, Swift) Team Lead

Feb - Apr 2015

- Fully functional game with Retro design, written purely in Swift
- Solve 2048 game with 4 different AI (Artificial Intelligence) algorithms

UW Info Session App (iOS, Objective-C, Python, GAE, Parse) *Individual*

Feb - May 2014

- · Mobile app for querying info sessions held in University of Waterloo
- Implemented all frontend app and backend service. Actively maintained for 3 years. 91 DAU during peak time

Freelance Projects (iOS, Swift)

- <u>Sexify</u> 🗗 Jun Oct 2016
 - Helped Archivum Inc. to create its iOS application. Created animated spritesheet view using SpriteKit
 - Used BDD with the help of Quick/Nimble framework. Used fastlane tools to automate the deployment
- <u>4AM</u> 🗗 Dec 2015 Mar 2016
 - Helped Rich DX Studio to create an iOS app to manage late night drinks and food events
 - Integrated with Firebase for real-time data and with multiple map services for location based events

Individual iOS Apps (iOS, Swift, Objective-C)

Jun 2014 - Jan 2015

- <u>Date Formatter</u> developer tool for verifying ISO 8601 date format with references
- Tap Tap Heart Rate 💆 mobile application for measuring heart rate. 1.5k MAU

UWaterloo Course Notifier (Python, HTML5, CSS3, GAE) Individual Dec 2013 - Jan 2014

- · Web app for querying updated course schedules and setting email alerts for course openings
- Developed business logic layer and designed easy-to-use webpages with clear and consistent UI

EDUCATION

University of Waterloo

Waterloo, Canada

· Master of Engineering, Major in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Sep 2013 - Jun 2015

• Concentration in Software Engineering

Southeast University

Nanjing, China

• Bachelor of Engineering Degree, Major in Electrical Engineering & Its Automation

Sep 2008 - Jun 2012